Comstock Park, MI. Comstock Park Congregational Church records, 1888-2021.
Congregational Library & Archives
Comstock Park, MI. Comstock Park Congregational Church records, 1888-2021.
1910 2021
1910-2021
RG5418
Congregational Library & Archives
8.37 Cubic Feet
(9 boxes)
On March 22, 1910, nineteen people gathered for a meeting called by Charles G. Marshall to discuss forming a church in order to fulfill the community's religious needs. As a result of the discussion, the Comstock Park Congregational Church officially formed with thirty-nine members on July 7, 1910. The church moved online once the Covid-19 pandemic started in 2020 and while they saw increased engagement online, it would not be enough to keep the church going. A final service was held in November 2020. This collection contains records from across the Churches life and includes various church organizations, financial documents, pastoral records, vital statistics, visual material, letters, histories, administrative records, reports, and meeting minutes.
Mellena, Joyce
Van Der Veen, Christian, 1838-1896
Barnes, Estle C., 1893-1964
Happel, Richard
Brosseit, Lawrence
Bohlert, Steve
Woodward, Dick
Comstock Park Congregational Church (Comstock Park, MI.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library by Joyce Mellena in March 2021; 2021-01.
Historical Note
On March 22, 1910, nineteen people gathered for a meeting called by Charles G. Marshall to discuss forming a church in order to fulfill the community's religious needs. As a result of the discussion, the Comstock Park Congregational Church officially formed with thirty-nine members on July 7, 1910. Reverend S. T. Morris would serve as the first minister until 1914 and helped get the church organized. The church entered the Grand Rapids Association of Congregational Churches on March 5, 1912.
The church building was originally occupied by a small Baptist congregation who transferred ownership of the building in 1915. A parsonage was donated in 1928 and both buildings were transferred to a new space donated by the North family. The building went through various upgrades and changes over the years but remained in the same location.
The church saw declines throughout the 1970s and at one point closure was recommended by the UCC Michigan Conference. The church rallied in the following years but a divisive minister in the early 2000s led to a diminished number of members. The church moved online once the Covid-19 pandemic started in 2020 and while they saw increased engagement online, it would not be enough to keep the church going. A final service was held in November 2020.
Ministers
S. T. Morris 1910-1914
Frank Folkerson 1914-1916
W. A. Hutchinson 1916
F. W. Sass 1916-1918
S. T. Morris 1918-1920
A. G. Beard 1921-1923
G. E. Hughes 1924-1927
E. C. Barnes 1928-1943
Herbert H. McConnell 1943-1953
Raymond. L. Broadway 1953-1957
Albutt Gardner, Jr. 1957-1959
R. Prescott - Interim Pastor 1959
R. White - Interim Pastor 1959
D. Brady 1959-1963
R. White - Interim Pastor 1964-1965
F. O. Olson 1965-1970
B. Swem - Interim Pastor 1970
R. Happel 1970-1976
G. O'Conner - Interim Pastor 1977-1978
Robert Livingston 1978-1986
R. McConnell - Interim Paston 1986
Lawrence Brosseit 1986-1997
Toby Stadden - Interim Pastor 1997-1999
Steve Bohlert 1999-2002
A. D. Vandlen 2003-2004
Dick M. Woodward 2004-2015
Karen H. Stokes 2016-2019
Lori Peach-Filban 2020
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records from the Comstock Park Congregational Church and includes various church organizations, financial documents, pastoral records, vital statistics, visual material, letters, histories, administrative records, reports, and meeting minutes.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into four series and sixteen sub-series. The records in each series has been arranged chronologically by start date except in the reports and meeting minutes.
Series 1: Pastoral records, 1888-1894, 1923-2003
Series 2: Church records, 1903-2021
Subseries 1: Vital statistics, 1903-2015
Subseries 2: Visual material, 1910-2010, undated
Subseries 3: Reports and meeting minutes, 1910-2020
Subseries 4: Administrative, 1937-2003
Subseries 5: Histories, 1951-1960, 1984, 2021
Subseries 6: Newsletters, 1959-2017
Subseries 7: Letters, 1961-2004
Series 3: Organizational records, 1910-2006
Subseries 1: Educational, 1910-1963, 1982-2006
Subseries 2: Deaconess Board, 1910-1987
Subseries 3: Ladies Aid Society, 1912-1941
Subseries 4: Miscellany groups, 1936-1947, 1975-1983
Subseries 5: Women's Fellowship, 1943-1971
Subseries 6: Misner Circle, 1946-1967
Subseries 7: Barnes Circle, 1960-1978
Subseries 8: Ladies Circle, 1962-1980
Subseries 9: Diaconate Council, 1984-1986, 2008-2009
Series 4: Financial records, 1923-2000
Technical Requirements
To access the CD's in this collection requires the use of a computer with disk drive.
Bibliography
1. DeBoer, Terry. "Behind the Closing Doors part 1 and 2" West Michigan Christian News, Jan. 14, 2021. 2. "Comstock Park Congregational Church Golden Anniversary". (Comstock Park, Michigan, 1960).
Vital statistics.; Church records and registers.; Church societies.; Installation (clergy).; Church finance.; Scrapbooks.; Photograph collections.; Letters.; Church newsletters.; Christian stewardship.; Christian education of children.; Comstock Park Congregational Church (Comstock Park, MI.)
- Pastoral records, 1888 2003; 1888-1894, 1923-2003; 15 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records related to pastors, such as sermons, call agreements, memories, services and a support form.
  - A Sermon by Christian Van Der Veen, August 19, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Heavenly Father by Paulo, October 31, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Is Love the Greatest Thing in the World by Christian Van Der Veen, February 10, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - On babies by Christian Van Der Veen, 1894-11-01 1894-11-30; November 1894 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Rev. Estle C. Barnes memories, 1923-1943, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Rev. Richard Happel call agreement, July 5, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Michigan Conference notice on call agreements, 1975-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Maundy Thursday services, 1975 1976; 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rev. Lawrence Brosseit call agreement, 1986-08-01 1986-10-31; August-October 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Thanksgiving sermon, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rev. Steve Bohlert call agreement, 1999-07-25 1999-07-26; July 25-26, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ministerial support form, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rev. Dick Woodward call agreement, December 31, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Call agreement templates, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Would I Dare be Rich?, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Pastor's data files, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Church records, 1903 2021; 1903-2021; 163 Folders
  This series contains church records such as vital statistics, visual materials, reports, meeting minutes, administrative, histories, newsletters, and letters.
  - Vital statistics, 1903 2015; 1903-2015; 32 Folders
    This sub-series contains vital statistics such as membership, baptisms, deaths, marriages, dismission requests, directories and officer lists.
    - Letters of dismission, 1903 1944; 1903-1944 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Church register, 1910 1954; 1910-1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters of dismission, 1910 1964; 1910-1961 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Vital statistics, 1910 1985; 1910-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Membership, 1912-1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Baptism certificates, 1935 1970; 1935-1970 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Letters of dismission, 1945 1963; 1945-1963 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Church register, 1954 1958; 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Church register, 1957 1972; 1957-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Baptismal records, 1960 1975; 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Letters of dismission, 1965 1986; 1965-1986 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Membership cards, 1965 1970; 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Marriage records, 1965 1971; 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Church directory, 1971 1979; 1971, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Membership forms, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Church directories, 1984 2005; 1984-2005 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Deaths, 1985 2000; 1985-2000 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - In Memoriam, 1987 1992; 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Letters of dismission, 1987 2012; 1987-2012 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Baptisms, 1988 2002; 1988-2002 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Marriage licenses, 1989 1999; 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Membership certificates, 1993 1997; 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Church officers, 1997 2001; 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Active membership list, December 31, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Active membership list with vital statistics, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Vital statistics, 2003 2012; 2003-2012 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Wedding information, 2003 2014; 2003-2014 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Marriage licenses, 2003 2015; 2003-2015 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Church directories, 2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Vital statistics for 2003 and 2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Genealogical research on Ericksen family, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Membership cards A-K, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Visual material, 1910 2010; 1910-2010, undated; 26 Folders
    This sub-series contains visual materials from the Church and includes scrapbooks, photos, drawings and maps.
    - Scrapbook of early history, 1910 1950; 1910-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1910 1952; 1910-1952 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Church maps, 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook (1 of 2), 1960 1979; 1960-1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook (2 of 2), 1960 1979; 1960-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1960 1980; 1960-1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1980 1984; 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 100 year anniversary scrapbook, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Church photos, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Grid layout for church packet, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Photos of the church, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Photo slides, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Photos of church families, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Photos (1 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Photos (2 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Photos (3 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Photos (4 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook (1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook (2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook (1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook (2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Architectural Drawings, undated (Box 9)
  - Reports and meeting minutes, 1910 2020; 1910-2020; 51 Folders
    This sub-series contains various reports and minutes, including Trustees minutes, annual reports, Council meeting minutes, UCC yearbook reports, Church committee reports, board minutes, clerk reports, and the nomination committee.
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1910 1915; 1910-1915 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1944 1945; 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1952 1955; 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1955 1958; 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1958 1963; 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1963 1968; 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Trustees meeting minutes, 1993 2003; 1993-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Annual reports, 1960 1964; 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Annual reports, 1965 1969; 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Annual reports, 1970 1973; 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Annual reports, 1974 1978; 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Annual reports, 1981 1985; 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Annual reports, 1986 1990; 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Annual reports, 1991 1995; 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Annual reports, 1996 2000; 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Annual reports, 2000 2004; 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Annual reports, 2005 2009; 2005-2009 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Annual meetings on CD, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Annual reports, 2011 2020; 2011-2020 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Closing of the church, 2020 2021; 2020-2021 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1977 1979; 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1985 1986; 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1987 1989; 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1989 1996; 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Council meeting minutes, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Council meeting minutes, 2011 2017; 2011-2017 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Council meeting minutes, 2017 2018; 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Council meeting minutes, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Church committee reports, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Church reports, 1910 1919; 1910-1919 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Church committee meeting minutes, 1910 1935; 1910-1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Church committee reports, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Church reports, 1920 1949; 1920-1949 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Board secretary minutes, 1941 1947; 1941-1947 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Clerk reports, 1951 1954; 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Congregational Christian Churches yearbook reports, 1954 1959; 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Board meeting minutes, 1956 1973; 1956-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - United Church of Christ reports, 1960 1969; 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Church council meeting minutes, 1960 1974; 1960-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1970 1975; 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - UCC local church yearbook report, 1970 1977; 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - UCC local church yearbook report, 1986 1990; 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - UCC local church yearbook reports, 1990 1997; 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Meeting minutes and reports, 1996 2000; 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Praise Worship service proposal, June 10, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Report of the Nomination Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Administrative, 1937 2003; 1937-2003; 19 Folders
    This sub-series contains administrative records such as constitutions, event reports, yearbooks and certificates.
    - Guests at the Annual Chicken Dinner, 1937 1939; 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Dedication and Anniversary services, 1949 1985; 1949-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Order of Worship, 1952 1953; 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Yearbooks, 1954 1956; 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Yearbooks, 1957 1959; 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - United Church of Christ presents Our Church, August 12, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Golden Anniversary pamphlet, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Lay Services for the Church, 1962 1963; 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Grand Rapids Association constitution and by-laws, 1973 1974; 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Constitution, January 27, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Certificates of service, 1980 1995; 1980-1995 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Annual spring festival, 1981 1983; 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Constitution, 1993-12-01 1993-12-31; December 1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Constitution, 1998-01-01 1998-01-31; January 1998 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Church and staff information, 2001 2003; 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Church survey, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Comstock Park program brochure, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Church manual and procedures, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Histories, 1951 2021; 1951-1960, 1984, 2021; 6 Folders
    This sub-series contains recorded histories of the church from the church historian and an article on the church's closure.
    - Records for the Church Historian, 1951 1954; 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Historical Log, 1957 1958; 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Histories, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Historian's records, 1984-01-01 1984-01-31; January 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Behind the Closing Doors by Terry DeBoer, 2021-01-14 2021-01-22; January 14-22, 2021 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Notes from a Comstock Park Church history talk, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1959 2017; 1959-2017; 24 Folders
    This sub-series contains newsletters including the Good Tidings, Parish Visitor and the Church Window.
    - Good tidings newsletter, 1959 1960; 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Good tidings newsletter, 1961 1963; 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - The Parish Visitor, 1971 1973; 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Newsletters, 1977 1978; 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Newsletters, 1981 1983; 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Newsletters, 1983 1985; 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - The Church Window, 1993 1994; 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - The Church Window, 1995 1996; 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - The Church Window, 1997 1998; 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - The Church Window, 1998 1999; 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - The Church Window, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - The Church Window, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - The Church Window, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - The Church Window, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - The Church Window, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - The Church Window, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - The Church Window, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - The Church Window, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - The Church Window, 2008 2009; 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Handles by Airietta Helsel, 2008 2010; 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - The Church Window, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - The Church Window, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - The Church Window, 2012 2013; 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - The Church Window, 2016 2017; 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letters, 1961 2004; 1961-2004; 5 Folders
    This sub-series contains various letters from and to the church.
    - Church letters, 1961 1967; 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Church letters, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Letters from Church to members, 1970 1977; 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondences, 1989 1999; 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Correspondences, 2001 2004; 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Organizational records, 1910 2006; 1910-2006; 40 Folders
  This series contains records for organizations such as the Deaconess Board, Ladies Aid Society, Women's Fellowship, Misner Circle, Barnes Circle, Ladies Circle, Diaconate council, educational groups, and more.
  - Educational, 1910 2006; 1910-1963, 1982-2006; 8 Folders
    This sub-series contains records related to various educational groups, such as the Sunday School, Young People's group, music department, and the board of Christian education.
    - Sunday School reports, 1910 1913; 1910-1913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Superintendent of Sunday School, 1910 1945; 1910-1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Pilgrim Fellowship and Young People's reports, 1919 1946; 1919-1946 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Young People's secretarial record, 1947 1952; 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sunday School records, 1961 1963; 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Attendance awards, 1982 2006; 1982-2006 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Board of Christian Education meeting minutes, 1992 1994; 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Music department annual report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Deaconess Board, 1910 1987; 1910-1987; 7 Folders
    This sub-series contains meeting and financial records of the Deaconess Board.
    - Deaconess Board meeting minutes, 1910 1942; 1910-1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Deaconess Board meeting reports, 1912 1921; 1912-1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Deaconess Board meeting reports, 1947 1948; 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Deaconess Board records, 1950 1952; 1950, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Deaconess Board finances, 1961 1969; 1961-1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Deaconess Board meeting reports, 1963 1973; 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Deaconess Board meeting minutes, 1964 1987; 1964-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ladies Aid Society, 1912 1941; 1912-1941; 5 Folders
    This sub-series contains financial records and meeting minutes of the Ladies Aid society.
    - Ladies Aid Society cash accounts, 1912 1930; 1912-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ladies Aid Society finances, 1930 1941; 1930-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ladies Aid Society meeting minutes, 1930 1935; 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ladies Aid Society records, 1932 1935; 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ladies Aid Society meeting minutes, 1935 1940; 1935-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellany groups, 1936 1983; 1936-1947, 1975-1983; 4 Folders
    This sub-series contains one-off records from groups such as the Ladies Guild, Leva Barnes Circle, Ethel Lamoreaux Circle, and the Frances Shaw Circle.
    - Ladies Guild records, 1936 1947; 1936-1947 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Leva Barnes Circle reports, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Ethel Lamoreaux Circle reports, 1946 1947; 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Frances Shaw Circle records, 1975 1983; 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Women's Fellowship, 1943 1971; 1943-1971; 6 Folders
    This sub-series contains reports, meeting minutes, financial records and by-laws of the Women's Fellowship.
    - Women's Fellowship treasurer's book, 1943 1949; 1943-1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Women's Fellowship annual report, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Women's Fellowship meeting minutes, 1950 1958; 1950-1958 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Women's Fellowship budgets, 1965 1973; 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Women's Fellowship meeting minutes, 1968 1971; 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Women's Fellowship by-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Misner Circle, 1946 1967; 1946-1967; 3 Folders
    This sub-series contains financial records of the Misner Circle.
    - Misner Circle treasurer reports, 1946 1950; 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Misner Circle treasurer reports, 1948 1962; 1948-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Misner Circle finance reports, 1962 1967; 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barnes Circle, 1960 1978; 1960-1978; 3 Folders
    This sub-series contains records and treasurer reports for the Barnes Circle.
    - Barnes Circle records, 1960 1961; 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Barnes Circle treasure reports, 1966 1971; 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Barnes Circle records, 1972 1978; 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ladies Circle, 1962 1980; 1962-1980; 2 Folders
    This sub-series contains records of the Ladies Circle.
    - Ladies Circle records, 1962 1967; 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Ladies Circle records, 1976 1980; 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Diaconate Council, 1984 2009; 1984-1986, 2008-2009; 2 Folders
    This sub-series contains meeting and council minutes for the Diaconate council. In the earlier records they spelled it "Diakonate" but the records seem to be for the same group.
    - Diakonate council meeting minutes, 1984 1986; 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Diaconate council meeting minutes, 2008 2009; 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Financial records, 1923 2000; 1923-2000; 28 Folders
  This series contains records related to finances and includes receipts, treasurer's reports, donations, building funds, budgets, non-profit reports, balance sheets, and parsonage records.
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1923 1945; 1923-1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)